<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://jeffchan.xyz</link>
    <description>
      A place full of English contents
    </description>
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C10 - The loss of the Titanic</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/22/c10-the-loss-of-the-titanic/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>The great ship, <em>Titanic</em>, sailed for New York from Southampton on April 10th, 1912. She was carrying 1,316 passengers and a crew of 891. Even by modern standards, the 46,000 ton <em>Titanic</em> was a <code class="highlighter-rouge">colossal</code> ship. At that time, however, she was not only the largest ship that had ever been built, but was regarded as unsinkable, for she had sixteen <code class="highlighter-rouge">watertight compartments</code>. Even if two of these were flooded, she would still be able to float. The <code class="highlighter-rouge">tragic</code> sinking of this great liner will always be remembered, for she went down on her first <code class="highlighter-rouge">voyage</code> with heavy loss of life.</p>

<p>Four days after setting out, while the <em>Titanic</em> was sailing across the icy waters of the North Atlantic, a huge <code class="highlighter-rouge">iceberg</code> was suddenly spotted by a <code class="highlighter-rouge">lookout</code>. after the alarm had been given, the great ship turned sharply to avoid a direct <code class="highlighter-rouge">collision</code>. The <em>Titanic</em> turned just in time, <code class="highlighter-rouge">narrowly</code> missing the immense wall of ice which rose over 100 feet out o f the water beside her. Suddenly, there was a slight <code class="highlighter-rouge">trembling</code> sound from below, and the captain went down to see what had happened. The noise had been so <code class="highlighter-rouge">faint</code> that no one thought that the ship had been damaged. Below, the captain realized to his horror that the <em>Titanic</em> was sinking <code class="highlighter-rouge">rapidly</code>, for five of her sixteen watertight compartments had already been flooded! The order to abandon ship was given and hundreds of people <code class="highlighter-rouge">plunged</code> into the icy water. As there were not enough lifeboats for everybody, 1,500 lives were lost.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/22/c10-the-loss-of-the-titanic/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    The great ship, *Titanic*, sailed for New York from Southampton on April 10th, 1912.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C09 - flying cats</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/21/c09-flying-cats/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>Cats never fail to <code class="highlighter-rouge">fascinate</code> human beings. They can be friendly and <code class="highlighter-rouge">affectionate</code> towards humans, but they lead <code class="highlighter-rouge">mysterious</code> lives of their own as well. They never become <code class="highlighter-rouge">submissive</code> like dogs and horses. As a result, humans have learned to respect <code class="highlighter-rouge">feline</code> independence. Most cats remain <code class="highlighter-rouge">suspicious</code> of humans all their lives. One of the things that fascinate us most about cats is the popular belief that they have nine lives. <code class="highlighter-rouge">Apparently</code>, there is a good deal of truth in this idea. A cat’s ability to survive falls is <code class="highlighter-rouge">based on</code> fact.</p>

<p>Recently the New York Animal Medical Centre made a study of 132 cats over a period of five months. All these cats had one experience in common: they had fallen off high buildings yet only eight of them died from shock or injuries. Of course, New York is the ideal place for such an interesting study, because there is no <code class="highlighter-rouge">shortage</code> of tall buildings. There are plenty of high-rise <code class="highlighter-rouge">windowsills</code> to fall from! One cat, Sabrina, fell 32 storeys, yet only suffered from a broken tooth. <em>‘Cats behave like well-trained <code class="highlighter-rouge">paratroopers</code>,’</em> a doctor said. It seems that the further cats fall, the less they are likely to injure themselves. In a long drop, they reach speeds of 60 miles an hour and more. At high speeds, falling cats have time to relax. They stretch out their legs like flying squirrels. This increases their <code class="highlighter-rouge">air-resistance</code> and reduces the shock of impact when they hit the ground.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/21/c09-flying-cats/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    Cats never fail to fascinate human beings.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C08 - A famous monastery</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/20/c08-a-famous-monastery/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>The Great St. Bernard Pass connects Switzerland to Italy. At 2,473 meters, it is the highest mountain pass in Europe. The famous <code class="highlighter-rouge">monastery</code> of St. Bernard, which was founded in the eleventh century, lies about a mile away. For hundreds of years, St. Bernard dogs have saved the lives of travellers crossing the dangerous Pass. These friendly dogs, which were first brought from Asia, were used as watchdogs even in Roman times. <code class="highlighter-rouge">Now that</code> a tunnel has been built through the mountains, the Pass is less dangerous, but each year, the dogs are still sent out into the snow whenever a traverller is in difficulty. Despite the new tunnel, there are still a few people who <code class="highlighter-rouge">rashly</code> attempt to cross the Pass on foot.</p>

<p>During the summer months, the monastery is very busy, for it is visited by thousands of people who cross the Pass in cars. <code class="highlighter-rouge">As there are so many people about</code>, the dogs have to be kept in a special <code class="highlighter-rouge">enclosure</code>. In winter, however, life at the monastery is quite different. The temperature drops to -30 and very few people attempt to cross the Pass. The <code class="highlighter-rouge">monks</code> prefer winter to summer for they have more privacy. The dogs have greater freedom, too, for they are allowed to wander outside their enclosure. The only regular visitors to the monastery in winter are parties of skiers who go there at Christmas and Easter. These young people, who love the peace of the mountains, always receive a warm welcome at St. Bernard’s monastery.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/20/c08-a-famous-monastery/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    The Great St.Bernard Pass connects Switzerland to Italy.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C07 - Mutilated ladies</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/19/c07-mutilated-ladies/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>Has it ever happened to you? Have you ever put your trousers in the washing machine and then remembered there was <code class="highlighter-rouge">a large back note</code> in you back pocket? When you rescued your trousers, did you find the notes was <code class="highlighter-rouge">whiter than white</code>? People who live in Britain needn’t despair when they make mistakes like this (and a lot of people do)! Fortunately for them, the Bank of England has a team called Mutilated Ladies which deals with claims from people who fed their money to a machine or to their dog. Dogs, it seems, love to <code class="highlighter-rouge">chew up</code> money!</p>

<p>A recent case concerns Jane Butlin whose <code class="highlighter-rouge">fiancé</code>, John, runs a successful furniture business. John had a very good day and put his wallet containing £3,000 into the microwave oven for safekeeping. Then he and Jane went horse-riding. When they got home, Jane cooked their dinner in the microwave oven and without realizing it, cooked her fiancé’s wallet as well. Imagine their <code class="highlighter-rouge">dismay</code> when they found a beautifully-cooked wallet and notes turned to ash! John went to see his bank manager who sent the remains of wallet and the money to the special department of the Bank of England in <code class="highlighter-rouge">Newcastle</code>: <code class="highlighter-rouge">the Mutilated Ladies</code> ! They examined the remains and John got all his money back. <em>‘So long as there’s something to identify, we will give people their money back,’</em> said a spokeswoman for the Bank. <em>‘Last year, we paid £1.5m on 21,000 claims.’</em>  <em>Damanged bank notes. The Queen’s head appears on English bank notes, and *‘lady’</em> refers to this.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/19/c07-mutilated-ladies/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    Has it ever happened to you? Have you ever put your trousers in the washing machine and then remembered there was a large back note in you back pocket?
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C06 - Smash-and-grab</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/18/c06-smash-and-grab/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>The expensive shops in a famous <code class="highlighter-rouge">arcade</code> near <code class="highlighter-rouge">Piccadilly</code> were just opening. At this time of the morning, the arcade was almost empty. Mr. Taylor, the owner of a jewellery shop was admiring a new window display. Two of his assistants had been working busily since eight o’colock and had only just finished. Diamond <code class="highlighter-rouge">necklaces</code> and rings had been beautifully arranged on a background of black <code class="highlighter-rouge">velvet</code>. After gazing at the display for several minutes, Mr. Taylor went back into his shop.</p>

<p>The silence was suddenly broken when a large car, with its headlights on and its <code class="highlighter-rouge">horn blaring</code>, roared down the arcade. It came to a stop outside the jeweller’s. One man stayed at the wheel while two others with black stockings  over their faces jumped out and <code class="highlighter-rouge">smashed</code> the windows of the shop with <code class="highlighter-rouge">iron bars</code>. While this was going on, Mr. Taylor was upstairs. He and his staff began throwing furniture out of the window. Chairs and tables went flying into the arcade. One of the thieves was struck by a heavy statue, but he was too busy helping himself to diamonds to notice any pain. The <code class="highlighter-rouge">raid</code> was all over in three minutes, for the men <code class="highlighter-rouge">scrambled</code> back into the car and it moved off at a <code class="highlighter-rouge">fantastic</code> speed. Just as it was leaving, Mr. Taylor rushed out and ran after it throwing ashtrays and vases, but it was impossible to stop the thieves. They had got away with thousands of pounds worth of diamonds.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/18/c06-smash-and-grab/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    The expensive shops in a famous arcade near Piccadilly were just opening. At this time of the morning, the arcade was almost empty.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C05 - The facts</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/17/c05-the-facts/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>Editors of newspapers and magazines often <code class="highlighter-rouge">go to extremes</code> to provide their readers with unimportant facts and <code class="highlighter-rouge">staticstics</code>. Last year a journalist had been instructed by a well-known magazine to write an article on the <code class="highlighter-rouge">president's palace</code> in a new African republic. When the article arrived, the editor read the first  sentence and then refused to publish it. The article began: <em>‘Hundreds of steps lead to the high wall which surrounds the president’s palace.’</em> The editor at once sent the journalist a fax instructing him to find out the exact number of steps and the height of the wall.</p>

<p>The journalist immediately set out to obtain these important facts, but he took a long time to send them. Meanwhile, the editor was getting impatient, for the magazine would soon <code class="highlighter-rouge">go to press</code>. He sent the journalist two more faxes, but received no reply. He sent yet another fax informing the journalist that if he did not reply soon he would be fired. When the journalist again failed to reply, the editor reluctantly published the article as it had originally been written. A week later, the editor as last received a fax from the journalist. Not only had the poor man been arrested, but he had been sent to prison as well. However, he had at last been allowed to send a fax in which he informed the editor that he had been arrested while counting the 1,084 steps leading to the fifteen-foot wall which surrounded the president’s palace.</p>


                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/17/c05-the-facts/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    Editors of newspapers and magazines often go to extremes to provide their readers with unimportant facts and staticstics.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C04 - The double life of Alfred Bloggs</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/16/c04-the-double-life-of-alfred-bloggs/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>These days, people who do manual work often receive far more money than people who work in offices. People who work in offices are frequently referred to as <em>‘white-collar works’</em> for the simple reason that they usually wear a <code class="highlighter-rouge">collar</code> and tie to go to work. Such is human nature, that a great many people are often willing to <code class="highlighter-rouge">sacrifice</code> higher pay for the <code class="highlighter-rouge">privilege</code> of becoming white-collar workers. This can give rise to curious situations, as it did in the case of Alfred Bloggs who worked as a dustman for the Ellesmere <code class="highlighter-rouge">Corporation</code>.</p>

<p>When he got married, Alf was too embarrassed to say anything to his wife about his job. He simply told her that he worked for the Corporation. Every morning, he left home dressed in a smart black suit. He then changed into <code class="highlighter-rouge">overalls</code> and spent the next eight hours as a dustman. Before returning home at night, he took a shower and changed back into his suit. Alf did this for over two years and his fellow dustmen kept his secret. Alf’s wife has never discovered that she married a dustman and she never will, for Alf has just found another job. He will soon be working in an office. He will be earning only half as much as he used to, but he feels that <code class="highlighter-rouge">his rise in status</code> is well worth the loss of money. From now on, he will wear a suit all day and others will call him ‘Mr.Bloggs’, not ‘Alf’.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/16/c04-the-double-life-of-alfred-bloggs/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    These days, people who do manual work often receive far more money than people who work in offices.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C03 - An unknown goddess</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/15/c03-an-unknown-goddess/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>Some time ago, an interesting discovery was made by <code class="highlighter-rouge">archaeologists</code> on the Aegean island of Kea. An American team explored a temple which stands in an ancient city <code class="highlighter-rouge">on the promontory of</code> Ayia Irini. The city at one time must have been <code class="highlighter-rouge">prosperous</code>, for it enjoyed a high level of civilization. Houses – often three <code class="highlighter-rouge">storeys</code> high – were built of stone. They had large rooms with beautifully decorated walls. The city was even equipped with a <code class="highlighter-rouge">drainage</code> system, for a great many <code class="highlighter-rouge">clay</code> pipes were found <code class="highlighter-rouge">beneath</code> the narrow streets.</p>

<p>The temple which the archaeologists explored was used as a place of <code class="highlighter-rouge">worship</code> from the fifteenth century B.C. until Roman times. In the most <code class="highlighter-rouge">sacred</code> room of the temple, clay <code class="highlighter-rouge">fragments</code> of fifteen <code class="highlighter-rouge">statues</code> were found. Each of these represented a goddess and had, at one time, been painted. The body of one statue was found among remains dating from the fifteenth century B.C. Its missing head happened to be among remains of the fifth century B.C. This head must have been found in Classical times and carefully preserved. It was very old and precious even then. When the archaeologists reconstructed the fragments, then were amazed to find that the goddess turned out to be a very modern-looking woman. She stood three feet high and her hands rested on her <code class="highlighter-rouge">hips</code>. She was wearing a full-length skirt which swept the ground. Despite her great age, she was very graceful indeed, but, so far, the archaeologists have been unable to discover her identity.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/15/c03-an-unknown-goddess/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    Some time ago, an interesting discovery was made by archaeologists on the Aegean island of Kea.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C02 - Thirteen equals one</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/14/c02-thirteen-equals-one/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>Our <code class="highlighter-rouge">vicar</code> is always raising money for one cause or another, but he has never managed to get enough money to have the church clock repaired. The big clock which used to strike the hours day and night was damaged many years ago and has been silent ever since.</p>

<p>One night, however, our vicar <code class="highlighter-rouge">woke up with a start</code>: the clock was striking the hours! Looking at his watch, he saw that it was one o’clock, but the bell struck thirteen times before it stopped. Armed with a <code class="highlighter-rouge">torch</code>, the vicar went up into the clock tower to see what was going on. In the torchlight, he caught sight of a figure whom he immediately recognized as Bill Wilkins, out local grocer.</p>

<p>“Whatever are you doing up here Bill?” asked the vicar in surprise.</p>

<p>“I’m trying to repair the bell, “ answered Bill. “I’ve been coming up here night after night for weeks now. You see, I was hoping to give you a surprise.”</p>

<p>“You certainly did give me a surprise!” said the vicar. “you’ve probably woken up everyone in the village as well. Still, I’m glad the bell is working again.”</p>

<p>“That’s the trouble, vicar, “ answered Bill. “It’s working all right, but I’m afraid that at one o’clock it will strike thirteen times and there’s nothing I can do about it.”</p>

<p>“We’ll get used to that, Bill, “ said the vicar. “Thirteen is not as good as one, but it’s better than nothing. Now let’s go downstairs and have a cup of tea. “</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/14/c02-thirteen-equals-one/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    Our vicar is always raising money for one cause or another, but he has never managed to get enough money to have the church clock repaired.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C01 - A puma at large</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/14/c01-a-puma-at-large/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>Pumas are large, cat-like animals which are found in America. When reports came into London Zoo that a wild puma had been spotted forty-five miles south of London, they were not taken seriously. However, as the evidence began to <code class="highlighter-rouge">accumulate</code>, experts from the Zoo <code class="highlighter-rouge">felt obliged to</code> investigate, for the descriptions given by people who claimed to have seen the puma were extraordinarily similar.</p>

<p>The hunt for the puma began in a small village where a woman picking blackberries saw ‘a large cat’ only five yards away from her. It immediately ran away when she saw it, and experts confirmed that a puma will not attack a human being unless it is cornered. The search proved difficult, for the puma was often observed at one place in the morning and at another place twenty miles away in the evening. Wherever it went, it left behind it a trail of dead deer and small animals like rabbits. Paw prints were seen in a number of places and puma fur was found <code class="highlighter-rouge">clinging to bushes</code>. Several people complained of ‘cat-like noises’ at night and a businessman on a fishing trip saw the puma up a tree. The experts were no fully convinced that the animal was a puma, but where had it come from ? As no pumas had been reported missing from any zoo in the country, this one must have been <code class="highlighter-rouge">in the possession of</code> a private collector and <code class="highlighter-rouge">somehow</code> managed to escape. The hunt went on for several weeks, but the puma was not caught. It is <code class="highlighter-rouge">disturbing</code> to think that a dangerous wild animal is still <code class="highlighter-rouge">at large</code> in the quiet countryside.</p>


                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/14/c01-a-puma-at-large/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    Pumas are large, cat-like animals which are found in America.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C11 - Not Guilty</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/12/c11-not-guilty/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>Customs Officers are quite <code class="highlighter-rouge">tolerant</code> these days, but they can still stop you when you are going through the <code class="highlighter-rouge">Green Channel</code> and have nothing to <code class="highlighter-rouge">declare</code>. Even really honest people are often made to feel guilty. The <code class="highlighter-rouge">hardened</code> professional <code class="highlighter-rouge">smuggler</code>, on the other hand, is never troubled by such feelings, even if he has five hundred gold watches hidden in his suitcase. When I returned from aboard recentlly, a particularly <code class="highlighter-rouge">officious</code> young Customs Officer clearly regarded me as a smuggler.</p>

<p><em>“Have you anything to declare ?”</em> he asked, looking me in the eye.</p>

<p><em>“No,”</em> I answered confidently.</p>

<p><em>“Would you mind unlocking this suitcase please?”</em></p>

<p><em>“Not at all”</em>,  I answered.</p>

<p>The Officer <code class="highlighter-rouge">went through</code> the case with great care. All the things I had packed so carefully were soon in a <code class="highlighter-rouge">dreadful</code> mess. I felt sure I would never be  able to close the case  again. Suddenly, I saw the Officer’s face light up. He had <code class="highlighter-rouge">spotted</code> a tiny bottle at the buttom of my case and  he <code class="highlighter-rouge">pounced</code> on it with delight.</p>

<p><em>“Perfume, eh?”</em> He asked <code class="highlighter-rouge">sarcastically</code>. <em>“You should have declared that. Perfume is not <code class="highlighter-rouge">exempt</code> from <code class="highlighter-rouge">import duty</code>.”</em></p>

<p><em>“But it isn’t perfume, “</em> I said. <em>“It’s hair gel. “</em> Then I added with a simle, <em>“It’s a strange mixture I make myself.”</em></p>

<p>As I expected, he did not believe me.</p>

<p><em>“Try it!”</em> I said encouragingly.</p>

<p>The Officer <code class="highlighter-rouge">unscrewed the cap</code> and put the bottle to his <code class="highlighter-rouge">nostrils</code>. He was greeted by an unpleasant smell which convinced him that I was telling the truth. A few minutes later, I was able to hurry away with <code class="highlighter-rouge">precious chalk marks</code> on my baggage.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/12/c11-not-guilty/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    Customs Officers are quite tolerant these days, but then can still stop you wen you are going through the Green Channel and have nothing to declare. Even really honest people are often made to feel guilt.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
  </channel>
</rss>
