<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://jeffchan.xyz</link>
    <description>
      A place full of English contents
    </description>
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C21 - Daniel Mendoza</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/02/18/c21-daniel-mendoza/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>Boxing matches were very popular in England two hundred years ago. In those days, boxer fought with bare fists for prize the money. Because of this, they were known as <em>‘prizefighters’</em>. However boxing was very <code class="highlighter-rouge">crude</code>, for there was no rules and <code class="highlighter-rouge">prizefighter</code> could be seriously injured or even killed during a match.</p>

<p>One of the most colourful figures of boxing history was Daniel Mendoza, who was born in 1764. The use of gloves was not introduced until 1860, when the <code class="highlighter-rouge">Mqrquis</code> of Queensberry drew up the first set of rules. Though he was <code class="highlighter-rouge">technically</code> a prizefighter, Mendoza did much to  change crude prizefighting into a sport, for he brought science to the game. <code class="highlighter-rouge">In his day</code>, Mendoza enjoyed <code class="highlighter-rouge">tremendous popularity</code>. He was <code class="highlighter-rouge">adored</code> by rich and poor alike.</p>

<p>Mendoza rose to  <code class="highlighter-rouge">fame</code> swiftly after a boxing match when he was only 14 years old. This attracted the attention of Richard Humphries  who was then the most <code class="highlighter-rouge">eminent</code> boxer in England. He offered to train Mendoza and his young  pupil was quick to learn. In facts, Mendoza soon become so successful that Humphries turned against him. The two men quarrelled <code class="highlighter-rouge">bitterly</code> and it was clear that the argument could only be settled by a fight. A match was held at Stilton, where both men fought for an hour. The public bet a great deal of money on Mendoza, but he was defeated. Mendoza Met Humphries in the ring on a later occasion and he lost for a second time. It was not until his third match in 1790 that he finally beat Humphries and became Champion of England. Meanwhile, he founded a highly successful <code class="highlighter-rouge">academy</code> and even Lord Byron became one of his pupils. He earned enormous sums of money and was paid as much as £100 for a single appearance. Despite this, he was so <code class="highlighter-rouge">extravagant</code> that he was always in debt. After he was defeated by a boxer called Gentleman Jackson, he was quickly forgotten. He was sent to prison for failing to pay his debts and died in <code class="highlighter-rouge">poverty</code> in 1836.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/02/18/c21-daniel-mendoza/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    Boxing matches were very popular in England two hundred years ago.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C20 - Pioneer pilots</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/02/14/c20-pioneer-pilots/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>In 1908 Lord Northcliffe offered a prize of £1,000 to the first man who would fly across the English Channel. Over a year passed before the first attempt was made. On July 19th, 1909, in the early morning, Hubert Latham took off from the French coast in his plane the <em>‘Antoinette IV’</em>. He had travelled only seven miles across the Channel when his engine failed and he was forced to land on the sea. The *‘Antoinette’ floated on the water until Latham was picked up by a ship.</p>

<p>Two days later, Louis Bleriot arrived near Calais with a plane called <em>‘No. XI’</em> . Bleriot had been making planes since 1905 and this was his latest model. A week before, he had completed a successful <code class="highlighter-rouge">overland</code> flight during which he covered twenty-six miles. Latham, however, did not give up easily. He, too, arrived near Calais on the same day with a new <em>‘Antoinette’</em> . It looked as if there would be an exciting race across the Channel. Both planes were going to take off on July 25th, but Latham failed to get up early enough. After making a short test flight at 4.15 a.m., Bleriot set off half an hour later. His great flight lasted thirty-seven minutes. When he landed near Dover, the first person to greet him was a local policeman. Latham made another attempt a week later and got within half a mile of Dover, but he was unlucky again. His engine failed and he landed on the sea for the second time.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/02/14/c20-pioneer-pilots/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    In 1908 Lord Northcliffe offered a prize of £1,000 to the first man who would fly across the English Channel.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C19 - A very dear cat</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/02/12/c19-a-very-dear-cat/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p><code class="highlighter-rouge">Kidnappers</code> are rarely interested in animals, but they recently took <code class="highlighter-rouge">considerable</code> interest in Mrs. Eleanor Ramsay’s cat. Mrs. Eleanor Ramsay, a very wealthy old lady, has shared a flat with her cat, Rastus, for a great many years. Rastus leads an <code class="highlighter-rouge">orderly</code> life. He usually takes a short walk in the evenings and it always home by seven o’ clock. One evening, however, he failed to arrive. Mrs. Ramsay got very worried. She looked everywhere for him but could not find him.</p>

<p>Three days after Rastus’ disappearance, Mrs. Ramsay received an <code class="highlighter-rouge">anonymous</code> letter. The writer stated that Rastus <code class="highlighter-rouge">was in safe hands</code> and would be returned immediately if Mrs. Ramsay paid a <code class="highlighter-rouge">ransom</code> of £1,000. Mrs. Ramsay was instructed to place the money in a cardboard box and to leave it outside her door. At first, she decided to go to the police, but fearing that she would never see Rastus again——the letter had made that quite clear——she changed her mind. She <code class="highlighter-rouge">withdrew</code> £1,000 from her bank and followed the kidnapper’s instruction. The next morning, the box had disappeared but Mrs. Ramsay was sure that the kidnapper would keep his word. <code class="highlighter-rouge">Sure enough</code>, Rastus arrived <code class="highlighter-rouge">punctually</code> at seven o’ clock that evening. He looked very well, though he was rather thirsty, for he drank half a bottle of milk. The police were <code class="highlighter-rouge">astounded</code> when Mrs. Ramsay told them what she had done. She explained that Rastus was very dear to her. Considering the amount she paid, he was dear in more ways than one!</p>


                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/02/12/c19-a-very-dear-cat/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    Kidnappers are rarely interested in animals, but they recently took considerable interest in Mrs. Eleanor Ramsay's cat.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C18 - Electric currents in modern art</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/30/c18-electric-currents-in-modern-art/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>Modern sculption rarely surprised us any more. The idea that modern art can only be seen in Museums is mistaken. Even people who take no interest in arts cannot have failed to notice examples of modern sculpture on display in public places. Strange forms stand in gardens, and outside buildings and shops. We have got quite used to them. Some so-called ‘modern’ pieces have been on display for nearly eighty years.</p>

<p><code class="highlighter-rouge">In spite of</code>, some people——including myself——were surprised by a recent exhibition of modern sculpture. The first thing I saw when I entered the art gallery was a notice which said: <em>‘Do not touch the exhibits. Some of them are dangerous!’</em> The objects on display were pieces of moving sculpture. Oddly shaped forms that are <code class="highlighter-rouge">suspended from ceiling</code> and move in response to <code class="highlighter-rouge">a gust of</code> wind are quite familiar to everybody. These objects, however, were different. Lined up against the wall, there were long thin wires attached to metal spheres. The spheres had been magnetized and attracted or repelled each other all the time. In the centre of the hall, there were a number of tall structures which contained colored lights. These lights flickered continuously like traffic lights which have gone mad. Sparks were. Emitted from small black boxes and red lamps flashed on and off angrily. It was rather like an exhibition of prehistoric electronic equipment. These peculiar forms not only seemed designed to shock people emotionally, but to give them electric shocks as well !</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/30/c18-electric-currents-in-modern-art/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    Modern sculption rarely surprised us any more.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C17 - The longest suspension bridge in the world</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/29/c17-the-longest-suspension-bridge-in-the-world/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>Verrazano, an Italian about whom little is known, sailed into New York Harbour in 1524 and named it Angouleme. He described it as a very <code class="highlighter-rouge">agreeable</code> situation located within two small hills in the midst of which flowed a great reiver. Though Verrazano is by no means considered to be a great explorer, his name will probably remain <code class="highlighter-rouge">immortal</code>, for on November 21st, 1964, the longest <code class="highlighter-rouge">suspension</code> bridge in the world was named after him.</p>

<p>The Verrazano Bridge, which was designed by Othmar Ammann, joins Brooklyn to Staten Island. It has a <code class="highlighter-rouge">span</code> of 4,260 feet. The bridge is so long that the shape of the earth had to be taken into account by its designer. Two great towers support four huge cables. The towers are build on <code class="highlighter-rouge">immense</code> underwater platforms made of steel and concrete. The platform extend to a depth of over 100 feet under the sea. These alone took sixteen months to build. Above the surface of the water, the towers rise to a height of nearly 700 feet. Then support the cable from which the bridge has been <code class="highlighter-rouge">suspended</code>. Each of the four cables contains 26,108 <code class="highlighter-rouge">lengths</code> of wire. It has been <code class="highlighter-rouge">estimated</code> that if the bridge were packed with cars, it would still only be carrying a third of its total <code class="highlighter-rouge">capacity</code>. However, size and strength are not the only important things about this bridge. Despite its <code class="highlighter-rouge">immensity</code>, it is both simple and <code class="highlighter-rouge">elegant</code>, fulfilling its designer’s dream to create an <code class="highlighter-rouge">enormous</code> object drawn as <code class="highlighter-rouge">faintly</code> as possible.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/29/c17-the-longest-suspension-bridge-in-the-world/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    Verrazano, an Italian about whom little is known, sailed into New York Harbour in 1524 and named it Angouleme.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C16 - Mary had a little lamb</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/29/c16-mary-had-a-little-lamb/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>Mary and her husband Dimitri lived in the tiny village of Perachora in southern Greece. One of Mary’s prize <code class="highlighter-rouge">possessions</code> was a little white lamb which her husband had given her. She kept it tied to a tree in a field during the day and went to fetch it every evening. One evening, however, the lamb was missing. The rope had been cut, so it was obvious that the lamb had been stolen.
  When Dimitri came in from the fields, his wife told him what had happened. Dimitri at once set out to find the thief. He knew it would not <code class="highlighter-rouge">prove</code> difficult in such a small village. After telling serveral of his friends about the <code class="highlighter-rouge">theft</code>, Dimitri found out that his neighbour, Aleko, had suddenly <code class="highlighter-rouge">acquired</code> a new lamb. Dimitri immediately went to Aleko’s house and angrily <code class="highlighter-rouge">accused him of</code> stealing the lamb. He told him he had better return it or he would call the police. Aleko denied taking it and led Dimitri into his backyard. It was true that he had just brought a lamb, he explained, but his lamb was black. Ashamed of having acted so rashly, Dimitri apologized to Aleko for having accused him. While they were talking it began to rain and Dimitri stayed in Aleko’s house until the rain stopped. When he went outside half an hour later, he was <code class="highlighter-rouge">astonished</code> to find that the little back lamb was almost white. Its wool, which had been <code class="highlighter-rouge">dyed</code> black, had been washed clean by the rain!</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/29/c16-mary-had-a-little-lamb/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    Mary and her husband Dimitri lived in the tiny village of Perachora in southern Greece.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C15 - fifty pence worth of trouble</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/27/c15-fifty-pence-worth-of-trouble/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>Children always appreciated small gifts of money. Mum or dad, of course, provide a regular money supply of <code class="highlighter-rouge">pocket money</code>, but uncles and aunts are always a source of extra income. With some children, small sums <code class="highlighter-rouge">go a long way</code>. If fifty pence pieces are not exchanged for sweets, they <code class="highlighter-rouge">rattle</code> for months inside money boxes. Only very <code class="highlighter-rouge">thrifty</code> children manage to fill up a money box. For most of them, fifty pence is a small price to pay for a nice big bar of chocolate.</p>

<p>My nephew, George, has a money box but it is always empty. Very few of the fifty pence pieces and pound coins I have given him have found their way there. I gave him fifty pence yesterday and <code class="highlighter-rouge">advised</code> him to save it. Instead he bought himself fifty pence <code class="highlighter-rouge">worth of trouble</code>. On his way to the sweet shop, he dropped his fifty pence and it <code class="highlighter-rouge">bounced</code> along the <code class="highlighter-rouge">pavement</code> and then disappeared down a drain. George took off his jacket, <code class="highlighter-rouge">rolled</code> up his <code class="highlighter-rouge">sleeves</code> and put his right arm through the drain cover. He could not find his fifty pence piece anywhere, and <code class="highlighter-rouge">what is more</code>, he could not get his arm out. <code class="highlighter-rouge">A crowd of</code> people <code class="highlighter-rouge">gathered</code> round him and a lady <code class="highlighter-rouge">rubbed</code> his arm with soap and butter, but George was <code class="highlighter-rouge">firmly</code> stuck. The <code class="highlighter-rouge">fire brigade</code> was called and two fire fighters freed George using a special type of <code class="highlighter-rouge">grease</code>. George was not too upset by his experience because the lady who owns the sweet shop heard about his troubles and rewarded him with a large box of chocolates.</p>


                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/27/c15-fifty-pence-worth-of-trouble/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    Children always appreciated small gifts of money.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C14 - A noble gangster</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/26/c14-a-noble-gangster/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>There was a time when the owner of shops and businesses in chicago had to pay large sums of money to <code class="highlighter-rouge">gangster</code> and <code class="highlighter-rouge">in return for</code> <em>‘protection’</em>. If the money was not paid <code class="highlighter-rouge">promptly</code>.  The gangster will quickly put a man <code class="highlighter-rouge">out of bussiness</code> by destroy his shop. Obtaining <em>‘protection money’</em> is not a modern crime. <code class="highlighter-rouge">As long ago as</code> the fourteen century, an Englishman Sir  John hwakwood made the remarkable discovery that people would rather pay large sums of money than have their life work destroy by gangsters.</p>

<p>Six hundred years ago, Sir John hawkwood arrived in Italy with <code class="highlighter-rouge">a band of</code> soldiers and settled near Florence. He soon <code class="highlighter-rouge">made a name for himself</code> and came to be known by Italians as  Giovanni Acuto. Whenever the Italian city-states were at war with each other. Hawkwood used to hired his soliders to <code class="highlighter-rouge">princes</code> who were wiling to pay the high price he demanded. <code class="highlighter-rouge">In times of peace</code>, when business was bad, hawkwood and his men would <code class="highlighter-rouge">march into</code> a city-state and, after burning down a few farms, would offer to go away if protection money was paid to them. Hawkwood made large sums of money in this way. <code class="highlighter-rouge">In spire of</code> this, the Italians regarded him as <code class="highlighter-rouge">a sort of </code> hero. When he died at the age of eighty, the Florentines gave him a state funeral and had a picture painted which was <code class="highlighter-rouge">dedicated</code> to the memory of <em>‘most <code class="highlighter-rouge">valiant</code> soldier and most <code class="highlighter-rouge">notable</code> leader, Signor Giovanni Haukodue’</em>.</p>


                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/26/c14-a-noble-gangster/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    There was a time when the owner of shops and businesses in chicago had to pay large sums of money to gangster and in return for 'protection'.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C13 - It's only me</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/25/c13-its-only-me/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>After her husband had gone to work, Mrs. Richards sent her children to school and went upstairs to her bedroom. She was too excited to do any housework that morning, for in the evening she would be going to a fancy-dress party with her husband. She intended to dress up as a ghost and as she had made her <code class="highlighter-rouge">costume</code> the night before, she was impatient to try it on. Though the costume <code class="highlighter-rouge">consisted only of</code> a sheet, it was very effective. After putting it on, Mrs. Richards went downstairs. She wanted to find out whether it would be comfortable to wear.</p>

<p>Just as Mrs. Richards was entering the <code class="highlighter-rouge">dining room</code>, there was a knock on the front door. She knew that it must be the baker. She had told him to come straight in <code class="highlighter-rouge">if ever</code> she failed to open the door and to leave the bread on the kitchen table. Not wanting to frighten the poor man, Mrs. Richards quickly hid in the small storeroom under the stairs. She heard the front door open and heavy footsteps in the hall. Suddenly the door of the storeroom was opened and a man entered. Mrs. Richards realized that it must be the man from the Electricity Board who had come to read the <code class="highlighter-rouge">metre</code>. She tried to explain the situation, saying <em>“It’s only me”</em>, but it was too late. The man let out a cry and jumped back several <code class="highlighter-rouge">paces</code>. When Mrs. Richards walked towards him, he <code class="highlighter-rouge">fled</code>, <code class="highlighter-rouge">slamming</code> the door behind him.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/25/c13-its-only-me/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    After her husband had gone to work, Mrs. Richards sent her children to school and went upstairs to her bedroom.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C12 - life on a desert island</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/24/c12-life-on-a-desert-island/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>Most of us have formed an unrealistic picture of life on a desert island. We sometimes imagine a desert island to be a sort of <code class="highlighter-rouge">paradise</code> where the sun always shines. Life there is simple and good. <code class="highlighter-rouge">Ripe</code> fruit falls from the trees and you never have to work. The other side of the picture is quite the opposite. Life on a desert island is <code class="highlighter-rouge">wretched</code>. You either starve to death or live like Robinson Crusoe, waiting for a boat which never comes. Perhaps there is an element of truth in both these pictures, but few of us have had the opportunity to find out.</p>

<p>Two men who recently spent five days on a <code class="highlighter-rouge">coral</code> island wished they had stayed there longer. They were taking a badly damaged boat from the Virgin Islands to Miami to have it repaired. During the journey, their boat began to sink. They quickly loaded a small <code class="highlighter-rouge">rubber dinghy</code> with food, matches, and cans of beer and rowed for a few miles across the Caribbean until they arrived at a tiny coral island. There were hardly any trees on the island and there was no water, but this did not prove to be a problem. The men collected rainwater in the rubber dinghy. As they had brought a <code class="highlighter-rouge">spear gun</code> with them, they had plenty to eat. They caught <code class="highlighter-rouge">lobster</code> and fish every day, and, as one of them put it ‘ate like kings’. When a passing <code class="highlighter-rouge">tanker</code> rescued them five days later, both men were <code class="highlighter-rouge">genuinely</code> sorry that they had to leave.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/24/c12-life-on-a-desert-island/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    Most of us have formed an unrealistic picture of life on a desert island.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C11 - Not Guilty</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/23/c11-not-guilty/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>Customs Officers are quite <code class="highlighter-rouge">tolerant</code> these days, but they can still stop you when you are going through the <code class="highlighter-rouge">Green Channel</code> and have nothing to <code class="highlighter-rouge">declare</code>. Even really honest people are often made to feel guilty. The <code class="highlighter-rouge">hardened</code> professional <code class="highlighter-rouge">smuggler</code>, on the other hand, is never troubled by such feelings, even if he has five hundred gold watches hidden in his suitcase. When I returned from aboard recentlly, a particularly <code class="highlighter-rouge">officious</code> young Customs Officer clearly regarded me as a smuggler.</p>

<p><em>“Have you anything to declare ?”</em> he asked, looking me in the eye.</p>

<p><em>“No,”</em> I answered confidently.</p>

<p><em>“Would you mind unlocking this suitcase please?”</em></p>

<p><em>“Not at all”</em>,  I answered.</p>

<p>The Officer <code class="highlighter-rouge">went through</code> the case with great care. All the things I had packed so carefully were soon in a <code class="highlighter-rouge">dreadful</code> mess. I felt sure I would never be  able to close the case  again. Suddenly, I saw the Officer’s face light up. He had <code class="highlighter-rouge">spotted</code> a tiny bottle at the buttom of my case and  he <code class="highlighter-rouge">pounced</code> on it with delight.</p>

<p><em>“Perfume, eh?”</em> He asked <code class="highlighter-rouge">sarcastically</code>. <em>“You should have declared that. Perfume is not <code class="highlighter-rouge">exempt</code> from <code class="highlighter-rouge">import duty</code>.”</em></p>

<p><em>“But it isn’t perfume, “</em> I said. <em>“It’s hair gel. “</em> Then I added with a simle, <em>“It’s a strange mixture I make myself.”</em></p>

<p>As I expected, he did not believe me.</p>

<p><em>“Try it!”</em> I said encouragingly.</p>

<p>The Officer <code class="highlighter-rouge">unscrewed the cap</code> and put the bottle to his <code class="highlighter-rouge">nostrils</code>. He was greeted by an unpleasant smell which convinced him that I was telling the truth. A few minutes later, I was able to hurry away with <code class="highlighter-rouge">precious chalk marks</code> on my baggage.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/23/c11-not-guilty/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    Customs Officers are quite tolerant these days, but then can still stop you wen you are going through the Green Channel and have nothing to declare. Even really honest people are often made to feel guilt.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C10 - The loss of the Titanic</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/22/c10-the-loss-of-the-titanic/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>The great ship, <em>Titanic</em>, sailed for New York from Southampton on April 10th, 1912. She was carrying 1,316 passengers and a crew of 891. Even by modern standards, the 46,000 ton <em>Titanic</em> was a <code class="highlighter-rouge">colossal</code> ship. At that time, however, she was not only the largest ship that had ever been built, but was regarded as unsinkable, for she had sixteen <code class="highlighter-rouge">watertight compartments</code>. Even if two of these were flooded, she would still be able to float. The <code class="highlighter-rouge">tragic</code> sinking of this great liner will always be remembered, for she went down on her first <code class="highlighter-rouge">voyage</code> with heavy loss of life.</p>

<p>Four days after setting out, while the <em>Titanic</em> was sailing across the icy waters of the North Atlantic, a huge <code class="highlighter-rouge">iceberg</code> was suddenly spotted by a <code class="highlighter-rouge">lookout</code>. after the alarm had been given, the great ship turned sharply to avoid a direct <code class="highlighter-rouge">collision</code>. The <em>Titanic</em> turned just in time, <code class="highlighter-rouge">narrowly</code> missing the immense wall of ice which rose over 100 feet out o f the water beside her. Suddenly, there was a slight <code class="highlighter-rouge">trembling</code> sound from below, and the captain went down to see what had happened. The noise had been so <code class="highlighter-rouge">faint</code> that no one thought that the ship had been damaged. Below, the captain realized to his horror that the <em>Titanic</em> was sinking <code class="highlighter-rouge">rapidly</code>, for five of her sixteen watertight compartments had already been flooded! The order to abandon ship was given and hundreds of people <code class="highlighter-rouge">plunged</code> into the icy water. As there were not enough lifeboats for everybody, 1,500 lives were lost.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/22/c10-the-loss-of-the-titanic/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    The great ship, *Titanic*, sailed for New York from Southampton on April 10th, 1912.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C09 - flying cats</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/21/c09-flying-cats/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>Cats never fail to <code class="highlighter-rouge">fascinate</code> human beings. They can be friendly and <code class="highlighter-rouge">affectionate</code> towards humans, but they lead <code class="highlighter-rouge">mysterious</code> lives of their own as well. They never become <code class="highlighter-rouge">submissive</code> like dogs and horses. As a result, humans have learned to respect <code class="highlighter-rouge">feline</code> independence. Most cats remain <code class="highlighter-rouge">suspicious</code> of humans all their lives. One of the things that fascinate us most about cats is the popular belief that they have nine lives. <code class="highlighter-rouge">Apparently</code>, there is a good deal of truth in this idea. A cat’s ability to survive falls is <code class="highlighter-rouge">based on</code> fact.</p>

<p>Recently the New York Animal Medical Centre made a study of 132 cats over a period of five months. All these cats had one experience in common: they had fallen off high buildings yet only eight of them died from shock or injuries. Of course, New York is the ideal place for such an interesting study, because there is no <code class="highlighter-rouge">shortage</code> of tall buildings. There are plenty of high-rise <code class="highlighter-rouge">windowsills</code> to fall from! One cat, Sabrina, fell 32 storeys, yet only suffered from a broken tooth. <em>‘Cats behave like well-trained <code class="highlighter-rouge">paratroopers</code>,’</em> a doctor said. It seems that the further cats fall, the less they are likely to injure themselves. In a long drop, they reach speeds of 60 miles an hour and more. At high speeds, falling cats have time to relax. They stretch out their legs like flying squirrels. This increases their <code class="highlighter-rouge">air-resistance</code> and reduces the shock of impact when they hit the ground.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/21/c09-flying-cats/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    Cats never fail to fascinate human beings.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C08 - A famous monastery</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/20/c08-a-famous-monastery/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>The Great St. Bernard Pass connects Switzerland to Italy. At 2,473 meters, it is the highest mountain pass in Europe. The famous <code class="highlighter-rouge">monastery</code> of St. Bernard, which was founded in the eleventh century, lies about a mile away. For hundreds of years, St. Bernard dogs have saved the lives of travellers crossing the dangerous Pass. These friendly dogs, which were first brought from Asia, were used as watchdogs even in Roman times. <code class="highlighter-rouge">Now that</code> a tunnel has been built through the mountains, the Pass is less dangerous, but each year, the dogs are still sent out into the snow whenever a traverller is in difficulty. Despite the new tunnel, there are still a few people who <code class="highlighter-rouge">rashly</code> attempt to cross the Pass on foot.</p>

<p>During the summer months, the monastery is very busy, for it is visited by thousands of people who cross the Pass in cars. <code class="highlighter-rouge">As there are so many people about</code>, the dogs have to be kept in a special <code class="highlighter-rouge">enclosure</code>. In winter, however, life at the monastery is quite different. The temperature drops to -30 and very few people attempt to cross the Pass. The <code class="highlighter-rouge">monks</code> prefer winter to summer for they have more privacy. The dogs have greater freedom, too, for they are allowed to wander outside their enclosure. The only regular visitors to the monastery in winter are parties of skiers who go there at Christmas and Easter. These young people, who love the peace of the mountains, always receive a warm welcome at St. Bernard’s monastery.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/20/c08-a-famous-monastery/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    The Great St.Bernard Pass connects Switzerland to Italy.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C07 - Mutilated ladies</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/19/c07-mutilated-ladies/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>Has it ever happened to you? Have you ever put your trousers in the washing machine and then remembered there was <code class="highlighter-rouge">a large back note</code> in you back pocket? When you rescued your trousers, did you find the notes was <code class="highlighter-rouge">whiter than white</code>? People who live in Britain needn’t despair when they make mistakes like this (and a lot of people do)! Fortunately for them, the Bank of England has a team called Mutilated Ladies which deals with claims from people who fed their money to a machine or to their dog. Dogs, it seems, love to <code class="highlighter-rouge">chew up</code> money!</p>

<p>A recent case concerns Jane Butlin whose <code class="highlighter-rouge">fiancé</code>, John, runs a successful furniture business. John had a very good day and put his wallet containing £3,000 into the microwave oven for safekeeping. Then he and Jane went horse-riding. When they got home, Jane cooked their dinner in the microwave oven and without realizing it, cooked her fiancé’s wallet as well. Imagine their <code class="highlighter-rouge">dismay</code> when they found a beautifully-cooked wallet and notes turned to ash! John went to see his bank manager who sent the remains of wallet and the money to the special department of the Bank of England in <code class="highlighter-rouge">Newcastle</code>: <code class="highlighter-rouge">the Mutilated Ladies</code> ! They examined the remains and John got all his money back. <em>‘So long as there’s something to identify, we will give people their money back,’</em> said a spokeswoman for the Bank. <em>‘Last year, we paid £1.5m on 21,000 claims.’</em>  <em>Damanged bank notes. The Queen’s head appears on English bank notes, and *‘lady’</em> refers to this.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/19/c07-mutilated-ladies/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    Has it ever happened to you? Have you ever put your trousers in the washing machine and then remembered there was a large back note in you back pocket?
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C06 - Smash-and-grab</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/18/c06-smash-and-grab/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>The expensive shops in a famous <code class="highlighter-rouge">arcade</code> near <code class="highlighter-rouge">Piccadilly</code> were just opening. At this time of the morning, the arcade was almost empty. Mr. Taylor, the owner of a jewellery shop was admiring a new window display. Two of his assistants had been working busily since eight o’colock and had only just finished. Diamond <code class="highlighter-rouge">necklaces</code> and rings had been beautifully arranged on a background of black <code class="highlighter-rouge">velvet</code>. After gazing at the display for several minutes, Mr. Taylor went back into his shop.</p>

<p>The silence was suddenly broken when a large car, with its headlights on and its <code class="highlighter-rouge">horn blaring</code>, roared down the arcade. It came to a stop outside the jeweller’s. One man stayed at the wheel while two others with black stockings  over their faces jumped out and <code class="highlighter-rouge">smashed</code> the windows of the shop with <code class="highlighter-rouge">iron bars</code>. While this was going on, Mr. Taylor was upstairs. He and his staff began throwing furniture out of the window. Chairs and tables went flying into the arcade. One of the thieves was struck by a heavy statue, but he was too busy helping himself to diamonds to notice any pain. The <code class="highlighter-rouge">raid</code> was all over in three minutes, for the men <code class="highlighter-rouge">scrambled</code> back into the car and it moved off at a <code class="highlighter-rouge">fantastic</code> speed. Just as it was leaving, Mr. Taylor rushed out and ran after it throwing ashtrays and vases, but it was impossible to stop the thieves. They had got away with thousands of pounds worth of diamonds.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/18/c06-smash-and-grab/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    The expensive shops in a famous arcade near Piccadilly were just opening. At this time of the morning, the arcade was almost empty.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C05 - The facts</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/17/c05-the-facts/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>Editors of newspapers and magazines often <code class="highlighter-rouge">go to extremes</code> to provide their readers with unimportant facts and <code class="highlighter-rouge">staticstics</code>. Last year a journalist had been instructed by a well-known magazine to write an article on the <code class="highlighter-rouge">president's palace</code> in a new African republic. When the article arrived, the editor read the first  sentence and then refused to publish it. The article began: <em>‘Hundreds of steps lead to the high wall which surrounds the president’s palace.’</em> The editor at once sent the journalist a fax instructing him to find out the exact number of steps and the height of the wall.</p>

<p>The journalist immediately set out to obtain these important facts, but he took a long time to send them. Meanwhile, the editor was getting impatient, for the magazine would soon <code class="highlighter-rouge">go to press</code>. He sent the journalist two more faxes, but received no reply. He sent yet another fax informing the journalist that if he did not reply soon he would be fired. When the journalist again failed to reply, the editor reluctantly published the article as it had originally been written. A week later, the editor as last received a fax from the journalist. Not only had the poor man been arrested, but he had been sent to prison as well. However, he had at last been allowed to send a fax in which he informed the editor that he had been arrested while counting the 1,084 steps leading to the fifteen-foot wall which surrounded the president’s palace.</p>


                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/17/c05-the-facts/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    Editors of newspapers and magazines often go to extremes to provide their readers with unimportant facts and staticstics.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C04 - The double life of Alfred Bloggs</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/16/c04-the-double-life-of-alfred-bloggs/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>These days, people who do manual work often receive far more money than people who work in offices. People who work in offices are frequently referred to as <em>‘white-collar works’</em> for the simple reason that they usually wear a <code class="highlighter-rouge">collar</code> and tie to go to work. Such is human nature, that a great many people are often willing to <code class="highlighter-rouge">sacrifice</code> higher pay for the <code class="highlighter-rouge">privilege</code> of becoming white-collar workers. This can give rise to curious situations, as it did in the case of Alfred Bloggs who worked as a dustman for the Ellesmere <code class="highlighter-rouge">Corporation</code>.</p>

<p>When he got married, Alf was too embarrassed to say anything to his wife about his job. He simply told her that he worked for the Corporation. Every morning, he left home dressed in a smart black suit. He then changed into <code class="highlighter-rouge">overalls</code> and spent the next eight hours as a dustman. Before returning home at night, he took a shower and changed back into his suit. Alf did this for over two years and his fellow dustmen kept his secret. Alf’s wife has never discovered that she married a dustman and she never will, for Alf has just found another job. He will soon be working in an office. He will be earning only half as much as he used to, but he feels that <code class="highlighter-rouge">his rise in status</code> is well worth the loss of money. From now on, he will wear a suit all day and others will call him ‘Mr.Bloggs’, not ‘Alf’.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/16/c04-the-double-life-of-alfred-bloggs/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    These days, people who do manual work often receive far more money than people who work in offices.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C03 - An unknown goddess</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/15/c03-an-unknown-goddess/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>Some time ago, an interesting discovery was made by <code class="highlighter-rouge">archaeologists</code> on the Aegean island of Kea. An American team explored a temple which stands in an ancient city <code class="highlighter-rouge">on the promontory of</code> Ayia Irini. The city at one time must have been <code class="highlighter-rouge">prosperous</code>, for it enjoyed a high level of civilization. Houses – often three <code class="highlighter-rouge">storeys</code> high – were built of stone. They had large rooms with beautifully decorated walls. The city was even equipped with a <code class="highlighter-rouge">drainage</code> system, for a great many <code class="highlighter-rouge">clay</code> pipes were found <code class="highlighter-rouge">beneath</code> the narrow streets.</p>

<p>The temple which the archaeologists explored was used as a place of <code class="highlighter-rouge">worship</code> from the fifteenth century B.C. until Roman times. In the most <code class="highlighter-rouge">sacred</code> room of the temple, clay <code class="highlighter-rouge">fragments</code> of fifteen <code class="highlighter-rouge">statues</code> were found. Each of these represented a goddess and had, at one time, been painted. The body of one statue was found among remains dating from the fifteenth century B.C. Its missing head happened to be among remains of the fifth century B.C. This head must have been found in Classical times and carefully preserved. It was very old and precious even then. When the archaeologists reconstructed the fragments, then were amazed to find that the goddess turned out to be a very modern-looking woman. She stood three feet high and her hands rested on her <code class="highlighter-rouge">hips</code>. She was wearing a full-length skirt which swept the ground. Despite her great age, she was very graceful indeed, but, so far, the archaeologists have been unable to discover her identity.</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/15/c03-an-unknown-goddess/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    Some time ago, an interesting discovery was made by archaeologists on the Aegean island of Kea.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C02 - Thirteen equals one</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/14/c02-thirteen-equals-one/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>Our <code class="highlighter-rouge">vicar</code> is always raising money for one cause or another, but he has never managed to get enough money to have the church clock repaired. The big clock which used to strike the hours day and night was damaged many years ago and has been silent ever since.</p>

<p>One night, however, our vicar <code class="highlighter-rouge">woke up with a start</code>: the clock was striking the hours! Looking at his watch, he saw that it was one o’clock, but the bell struck thirteen times before it stopped. Armed with a <code class="highlighter-rouge">torch</code>, the vicar went up into the clock tower to see what was going on. In the torchlight, he caught sight of a figure whom he immediately recognized as Bill Wilkins, out local grocer.</p>

<p>“Whatever are you doing up here Bill?” asked the vicar in surprise.</p>

<p>“I’m trying to repair the bell, “ answered Bill. “I’ve been coming up here night after night for weeks now. You see, I was hoping to give you a surprise.”</p>

<p>“You certainly did give me a surprise!” said the vicar. “you’ve probably woken up everyone in the village as well. Still, I’m glad the bell is working again.”</p>

<p>“That’s the trouble, vicar, “ answered Bill. “It’s working all right, but I’m afraid that at one o’clock it will strike thirteen times and there’s nothing I can do about it.”</p>

<p>“We’ll get used to that, Bill, “ said the vicar. “Thirteen is not as good as one, but it’s better than nothing. Now let’s go downstairs and have a cup of tea. “</p>

                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/14/c02-thirteen-equals-one/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    Our vicar is always raising money for one cause or another, but he has never managed to get enough money to have the church clock repaired.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
        
            <item>
                <title>C01 - A puma at large</title>
                <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/14/c01-a-puma-at-large/</link>
                <content:encoded>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <p>Pumas are large, cat-like animals which are found in America. When reports came into London Zoo that a wild puma had been spotted forty-five miles south of London, they were not taken seriously. However, as the evidence began to <code class="highlighter-rouge">accumulate</code>, experts from the Zoo <code class="highlighter-rouge">felt obliged to</code> investigate, for the descriptions given by people who claimed to have seen the puma were extraordinarily similar.</p>

<p>The hunt for the puma began in a small village where a woman picking blackberries saw ‘a large cat’ only five yards away from her. It immediately ran away when she saw it, and experts confirmed that a puma will not attack a human being unless it is cornered. The search proved difficult, for the puma was often observed at one place in the morning and at another place twenty miles away in the evening. Wherever it went, it left behind it a trail of dead deer and small animals like rabbits. Paw prints were seen in a number of places and puma fur was found <code class="highlighter-rouge">clinging to bushes</code>. Several people complained of ‘cat-like noises’ at night and a businessman on a fishing trip saw the puma up a tree. The experts were no fully convinced that the animal was a puma, but where had it come from ? As no pumas had been reported missing from any zoo in the country, this one must have been <code class="highlighter-rouge">in the possession of</code> a private collector and <code class="highlighter-rouge">somehow</code> managed to escape. The hunt went on for several weeks, but the puma was not caught. It is <code class="highlighter-rouge">disturbing</code> to think that a dangerous wild animal is still <code class="highlighter-rouge">at large</code> in the quiet countryside.</p>


                    ]]>
                </content:encoded>
                <guid isPermaLink="false">/2019/01/14/c01-a-puma-at-large/</guid>
                <description>
                    
                    Pumas are large, cat-like animals which are found in America.
                    
                </description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <author>Jeff</author>
            </item>
        
    
  </channel>
</rss>
