<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>New-Concept</title>
    <description>A place full of English contents</description>
    <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://jeffchan.xyz/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>C16 - Mary had a little lamb</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Mary and her husband Dimitri lived in the tiny village of Perachora in southern Greece. One of Mary’s prize &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;possessions&lt;/code&gt; was a little white lamb which her husband had given her. She kept it tied to a tree in a field during the day and went to fetch it every evening. One evening, however, the lamb was missing. The rope had been cut, so it was obvious that the lamb had been stolen.
  When Dimitri came in from the fields, his wife told him what had happened. Dimitri at once set out to find the thief. He knew it would not &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;prove&lt;/code&gt; difficult in such a small village. After telling serveral of his friends about the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;theft&lt;/code&gt;, Dimitri found out that his neighbour, Aleko, had suddenly &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;acquired&lt;/code&gt; a new lamb. Dimitri immediately went to Aleko’s house and angrily &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;accused him of&lt;/code&gt; stealing the lamb. He told him he had better return it or he would call the police. Aleko denied taking it and led Dimitri into his backyard. It was true that he had just brought a lamb, he explained, but his lamb was black. Ashamed of having acted so rashly, Dimitri apologized to Aleko for having accused him. While they were talking it began to rain and Dimitri stayed in Aleko’s house until the rain stopped. When he went outside half an hour later, he was &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;astonished&lt;/code&gt; to find that the little back lamb was almost white. Its wool, which had been &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dyed&lt;/code&gt; black, had been washed clean by the rain!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/29/c16-mary-had-a-little-lamb/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/29/c16-mary-had-a-little-lamb/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>C15 - fifty pence worth of trouble</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Children always appreciated small gifts of money. Mum or dad, of course, provide a regular money supply of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pocket money&lt;/code&gt;, but uncles and aunts are always a source of extra income. With some children, small sums &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;go a long way&lt;/code&gt;. If fifty pence pieces are not exchanged for sweets, they &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rattle&lt;/code&gt; for months inside money boxes. Only very &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;thrifty&lt;/code&gt; children manage to fill up a money box. For most of them, fifty pence is a small price to pay for a nice big bar of chocolate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My nephew, George, has a money box but it is always empty. Very few of the fifty pence pieces and pound coins I have given him have found their way there. I gave him fifty pence yesterday and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;advised&lt;/code&gt; him to save it. Instead he bought himself fifty pence &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;worth of trouble&lt;/code&gt;. On his way to the sweet shop, he dropped his fifty pence and it &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bounced&lt;/code&gt; along the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pavement&lt;/code&gt; and then disappeared down a drain. George took off his jacket, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rolled&lt;/code&gt; up his &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sleeves&lt;/code&gt; and put his right arm through the drain cover. He could not find his fifty pence piece anywhere, and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;what is more&lt;/code&gt;, he could not get his arm out. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;A crowd of&lt;/code&gt; people &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gathered&lt;/code&gt; round him and a lady &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rubbed&lt;/code&gt; his arm with soap and butter, but George was &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;firmly&lt;/code&gt; stuck. The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;fire brigade&lt;/code&gt; was called and two fire fighters freed George using a special type of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;grease&lt;/code&gt;. George was not too upset by his experience because the lady who owns the sweet shop heard about his troubles and rewarded him with a large box of chocolates.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/27/c15-fifty-pence-worth-of-trouble/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/27/c15-fifty-pence-worth-of-trouble/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>C14 - A noble gangster</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There was a time when the owner of shops and businesses in chicago had to pay large sums of money to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gangster&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;in return for&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;‘protection’&lt;/em&gt;. If the money was not paid &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;promptly&lt;/code&gt;.  The gangster will quickly put a man &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;out of bussiness&lt;/code&gt; by destroy his shop. Obtaining &lt;em&gt;‘protection money’&lt;/em&gt; is not a modern crime. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;As long ago as&lt;/code&gt; the fourteen century, an Englishman Sir  John hwakwood made the remarkable discovery that people would rather pay large sums of money than have their life work destroy by gangsters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six hundred years ago, Sir John hawkwood arrived in Italy with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a band of&lt;/code&gt; soldiers and settled near Florence. He soon &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;made a name for himself&lt;/code&gt; and came to be known by Italians as  Giovanni Acuto. Whenever the Italian city-states were at war with each other. Hawkwood used to hired his soliders to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;princes&lt;/code&gt; who were wiling to pay the high price he demanded. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;In times of peace&lt;/code&gt;, when business was bad, hawkwood and his men would &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;march into&lt;/code&gt; a city-state and, after burning down a few farms, would offer to go away if protection money was paid to them. Hawkwood made large sums of money in this way. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;In spire of&lt;/code&gt; this, the Italians regarded him as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a sort of &lt;/code&gt; hero. When he died at the age of eighty, the Florentines gave him a state funeral and had a picture painted which was &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dedicated&lt;/code&gt; to the memory of &lt;em&gt;‘most &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;valiant&lt;/code&gt; soldier and most &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;notable&lt;/code&gt; leader, Signor Giovanni Haukodue’&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/26/c14-a-noble-gangster/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/26/c14-a-noble-gangster/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>C13 - It's only me</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After her husband had gone to work, Mrs. Richards sent her children to school and went upstairs to her bedroom. She was too excited to do any housework that morning, for in the evening she would be going to a fancy-dress party with her husband. She intended to dress up as a ghost and as she had made her &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;costume&lt;/code&gt; the night before, she was impatient to try it on. Though the costume &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;consisted only of&lt;/code&gt; a sheet, it was very effective. After putting it on, Mrs. Richards went downstairs. She wanted to find out whether it would be comfortable to wear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as Mrs. Richards was entering the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dining room&lt;/code&gt;, there was a knock on the front door. She knew that it must be the baker. She had told him to come straight in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;if ever&lt;/code&gt; she failed to open the door and to leave the bread on the kitchen table. Not wanting to frighten the poor man, Mrs. Richards quickly hid in the small storeroom under the stairs. She heard the front door open and heavy footsteps in the hall. Suddenly the door of the storeroom was opened and a man entered. Mrs. Richards realized that it must be the man from the Electricity Board who had come to read the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;metre&lt;/code&gt;. She tried to explain the situation, saying &lt;em&gt;“It’s only me”&lt;/em&gt;, but it was too late. The man let out a cry and jumped back several &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;paces&lt;/code&gt;. When Mrs. Richards walked towards him, he &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;fled&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;slamming&lt;/code&gt; the door behind him.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/25/c13-its-only-me/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/25/c13-its-only-me/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>C12 - life on a desert island</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Most of us have formed an unrealistic picture of life on a desert island. We sometimes imagine a desert island to be a sort of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;paradise&lt;/code&gt; where the sun always shines. Life there is simple and good. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Ripe&lt;/code&gt; fruit falls from the trees and you never have to work. The other side of the picture is quite the opposite. Life on a desert island is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wretched&lt;/code&gt;. You either starve to death or live like Robinson Crusoe, waiting for a boat which never comes. Perhaps there is an element of truth in both these pictures, but few of us have had the opportunity to find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two men who recently spent five days on a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;coral&lt;/code&gt; island wished they had stayed there longer. They were taking a badly damaged boat from the Virgin Islands to Miami to have it repaired. During the journey, their boat began to sink. They quickly loaded a small &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rubber dinghy&lt;/code&gt; with food, matches, and cans of beer and rowed for a few miles across the Caribbean until they arrived at a tiny coral island. There were hardly any trees on the island and there was no water, but this did not prove to be a problem. The men collected rainwater in the rubber dinghy. As they had brought a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;spear gun&lt;/code&gt; with them, they had plenty to eat. They caught &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lobster&lt;/code&gt; and fish every day, and, as one of them put it ‘ate like kings’. When a passing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tanker&lt;/code&gt; rescued them five days later, both men were &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;genuinely&lt;/code&gt; sorry that they had to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/24/c12-life-on-a-desert-island/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/24/c12-life-on-a-desert-island/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>C11 - Not Guilty</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Customs Officers are quite &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tolerant&lt;/code&gt; these days, but they can still stop you when you are going through the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Green Channel&lt;/code&gt; and have nothing to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;declare&lt;/code&gt;. Even really honest people are often made to feel guilty. The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;hardened&lt;/code&gt; professional &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;smuggler&lt;/code&gt;, on the other hand, is never troubled by such feelings, even if he has five hundred gold watches hidden in his suitcase. When I returned from aboard recentlly, a particularly &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;officious&lt;/code&gt; young Customs Officer clearly regarded me as a smuggler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Have you anything to declare ?”&lt;/em&gt; he asked, looking me in the eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“No,”&lt;/em&gt; I answered confidently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Would you mind unlocking this suitcase please?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Not at all”&lt;/em&gt;,  I answered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Officer &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;went through&lt;/code&gt; the case with great care. All the things I had packed so carefully were soon in a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dreadful&lt;/code&gt; mess. I felt sure I would never be  able to close the case  again. Suddenly, I saw the Officer’s face light up. He had &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;spotted&lt;/code&gt; a tiny bottle at the buttom of my case and  he &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pounced&lt;/code&gt; on it with delight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Perfume, eh?”&lt;/em&gt; He asked &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sarcastically&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;em&gt;“You should have declared that. Perfume is not &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exempt&lt;/code&gt; from &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;import duty&lt;/code&gt;.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“But it isn’t perfume, “&lt;/em&gt; I said. &lt;em&gt;“It’s hair gel. “&lt;/em&gt; Then I added with a simle, &lt;em&gt;“It’s a strange mixture I make myself.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I expected, he did not believe me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Try it!”&lt;/em&gt; I said encouragingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Officer &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;unscrewed the cap&lt;/code&gt; and put the bottle to his &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nostrils&lt;/code&gt;. He was greeted by an unpleasant smell which convinced him that I was telling the truth. A few minutes later, I was able to hurry away with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;precious chalk marks&lt;/code&gt; on my baggage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/23/c11-not-guilty/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/23/c11-not-guilty/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>C10 - The loss of the Titanic</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The great ship, &lt;em&gt;Titanic&lt;/em&gt;, sailed for New York from Southampton on April 10th, 1912. She was carrying 1,316 passengers and a crew of 891. Even by modern standards, the 46,000 ton &lt;em&gt;Titanic&lt;/em&gt; was a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;colossal&lt;/code&gt; ship. At that time, however, she was not only the largest ship that had ever been built, but was regarded as unsinkable, for she had sixteen &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;watertight compartments&lt;/code&gt;. Even if two of these were flooded, she would still be able to float. The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tragic&lt;/code&gt; sinking of this great liner will always be remembered, for she went down on her first &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;voyage&lt;/code&gt; with heavy loss of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four days after setting out, while the &lt;em&gt;Titanic&lt;/em&gt; was sailing across the icy waters of the North Atlantic, a huge &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;iceberg&lt;/code&gt; was suddenly spotted by a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lookout&lt;/code&gt;. after the alarm had been given, the great ship turned sharply to avoid a direct &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;collision&lt;/code&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;Titanic&lt;/em&gt; turned just in time, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;narrowly&lt;/code&gt; missing the immense wall of ice which rose over 100 feet out o f the water beside her. Suddenly, there was a slight &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;trembling&lt;/code&gt; sound from below, and the captain went down to see what had happened. The noise had been so &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;faint&lt;/code&gt; that no one thought that the ship had been damaged. Below, the captain realized to his horror that the &lt;em&gt;Titanic&lt;/em&gt; was sinking &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rapidly&lt;/code&gt;, for five of her sixteen watertight compartments had already been flooded! The order to abandon ship was given and hundreds of people &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;plunged&lt;/code&gt; into the icy water. As there were not enough lifeboats for everybody, 1,500 lives were lost.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/22/c10-the-loss-of-the-titanic/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/22/c10-the-loss-of-the-titanic/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>C09 - flying cats</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cats never fail to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;fascinate&lt;/code&gt; human beings. They can be friendly and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;affectionate&lt;/code&gt; towards humans, but they lead &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mysterious&lt;/code&gt; lives of their own as well. They never become &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;submissive&lt;/code&gt; like dogs and horses. As a result, humans have learned to respect &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;feline&lt;/code&gt; independence. Most cats remain &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;suspicious&lt;/code&gt; of humans all their lives. One of the things that fascinate us most about cats is the popular belief that they have nine lives. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Apparently&lt;/code&gt;, there is a good deal of truth in this idea. A cat’s ability to survive falls is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;based on&lt;/code&gt; fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently the New York Animal Medical Centre made a study of 132 cats over a period of five months. All these cats had one experience in common: they had fallen off high buildings yet only eight of them died from shock or injuries. Of course, New York is the ideal place for such an interesting study, because there is no &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;shortage&lt;/code&gt; of tall buildings. There are plenty of high-rise &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;windowsills&lt;/code&gt; to fall from! One cat, Sabrina, fell 32 storeys, yet only suffered from a broken tooth. &lt;em&gt;‘Cats behave like well-trained &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;paratroopers&lt;/code&gt;,’&lt;/em&gt; a doctor said. It seems that the further cats fall, the less they are likely to injure themselves. In a long drop, they reach speeds of 60 miles an hour and more. At high speeds, falling cats have time to relax. They stretch out their legs like flying squirrels. This increases their &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;air-resistance&lt;/code&gt; and reduces the shock of impact when they hit the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/21/c09-flying-cats/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/21/c09-flying-cats/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>C08 - A famous monastery</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Great St. Bernard Pass connects Switzerland to Italy. At 2,473 meters, it is the highest mountain pass in Europe. The famous &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;monastery&lt;/code&gt; of St. Bernard, which was founded in the eleventh century, lies about a mile away. For hundreds of years, St. Bernard dogs have saved the lives of travellers crossing the dangerous Pass. These friendly dogs, which were first brought from Asia, were used as watchdogs even in Roman times. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Now that&lt;/code&gt; a tunnel has been built through the mountains, the Pass is less dangerous, but each year, the dogs are still sent out into the snow whenever a traverller is in difficulty. Despite the new tunnel, there are still a few people who &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rashly&lt;/code&gt; attempt to cross the Pass on foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the summer months, the monastery is very busy, for it is visited by thousands of people who cross the Pass in cars. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;As there are so many people about&lt;/code&gt;, the dogs have to be kept in a special &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;enclosure&lt;/code&gt;. In winter, however, life at the monastery is quite different. The temperature drops to -30 and very few people attempt to cross the Pass. The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;monks&lt;/code&gt; prefer winter to summer for they have more privacy. The dogs have greater freedom, too, for they are allowed to wander outside their enclosure. The only regular visitors to the monastery in winter are parties of skiers who go there at Christmas and Easter. These young people, who love the peace of the mountains, always receive a warm welcome at St. Bernard’s monastery.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/20/c08-a-famous-monastery/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/20/c08-a-famous-monastery/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>C07 - Mutilated ladies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Has it ever happened to you? Have you ever put your trousers in the washing machine and then remembered there was &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a large back note&lt;/code&gt; in you back pocket? When you rescued your trousers, did you find the notes was &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;whiter than white&lt;/code&gt;? People who live in Britain needn’t despair when they make mistakes like this (and a lot of people do)! Fortunately for them, the Bank of England has a team called Mutilated Ladies which deals with claims from people who fed their money to a machine or to their dog. Dogs, it seems, love to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;chew up&lt;/code&gt; money!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recent case concerns Jane Butlin whose &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;fiancé&lt;/code&gt;, John, runs a successful furniture business. John had a very good day and put his wallet containing £3,000 into the microwave oven for safekeeping. Then he and Jane went horse-riding. When they got home, Jane cooked their dinner in the microwave oven and without realizing it, cooked her fiancé’s wallet as well. Imagine their &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dismay&lt;/code&gt; when they found a beautifully-cooked wallet and notes turned to ash! John went to see his bank manager who sent the remains of wallet and the money to the special department of the Bank of England in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Newcastle&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;the Mutilated Ladies&lt;/code&gt; ! They examined the remains and John got all his money back. &lt;em&gt;‘So long as there’s something to identify, we will give people their money back,’&lt;/em&gt; said a spokeswoman for the Bank. &lt;em&gt;‘Last year, we paid £1.5m on 21,000 claims.’&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;em&gt;Damanged bank notes. The Queen’s head appears on English bank notes, and *‘lady’&lt;/em&gt; refers to this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/19/c07-mutilated-ladies/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeffchan.xyz/2019/01/19/c07-mutilated-ladies/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
